# **Joseph Thomas**



103 Old Meadow Lane, Waterloo, ON iosephthomas780@gmail.com LinkedIn





# Professional Summary \_\_\_

Skilled customer service professional with over 7 years of successful client services, management, and leadership experience. Strong dedication to helping customers resolve issues and cultivating a positive image of the company. Excel in both team environments and alone. Dedicated to bettering the customer experience with reliable product education, timely assistance, helpful feedback, and respectful conflict management response.

#### Skills

- MS Office | Salesforce | Application Troubleshooting | Conflict Management | Multitasking | Collaboration
- Strong Administration | Organizational | Continual Improvement | Time management | Customer needs.
- Banking solutions | Business processes | Active listening | Good planning | recommends solutions | Promotion.
- Problem Solving | Teamwork | Relationship management. | Operational excellence. | Dedicated | Operating procedures.

### Professional Experience

#### Associate Technical Engineer, Support

# **Finastra Software Solutions**

02/2018 to 04/2023

- Acted as the Customer experience associate for support needs and increase first-call resolution from 15% to 40%
- Provide on-phone and online Support for users to facilitate the effective usage of the application improving 70% of the usability.
- Led the Continual Improvement team and increased Support process efficiency by 60%
- Respond to and resolve customers' concerns using standard procedures and escalating the tickets timely.
- Achieved a 99% customer feedback score in the first month of employment and maintained it constantly ever since.
- Played a key role in the successful launch of a new customer self-service portal, providing extensive training and support to customers, resulting in a 30% decrease in support ticket volume.

#### **Data Analyst**

#### **Binary Fountain Solutions**

03/2016 to 01/2018

- Supporting customers through ticket handling, Process documentation.
- Monitoring the automated reports in detail and with accuracy.
- Effectively managed multiple projects to ensure delivery dates are met.
- · Creating reports based on management needs.
- Document software enhancements, defects, and dashboard improvements.

#### Education

#### Ontario College Graduate Certificate

Conestoga College, Kitchener

Currently pursuing.

Reporting Systems and Database Development

#### Bachelor of Technology

**Jyothi Engineering College** 

05/2011 to 09/2015

Major in Electronics and Communication Engineering

# Awards and Honors

- Best Employee award for outstanding performance in customer support
- Company-wide recognition for maintaining a 99% customer satisfaction rating.

References are available on request.